Privacy Questions and Answers
=============================

This notice describes how Aragon Ventures collects and uses data about you.

What is Aragon Ventures?
------------------------

Aragon Ventures LLC (d/b/a [NABLA HOST](https://nabla.host/)) is an online service provider and web hosting company operated by Jonah Aragon in Minnesota, United States. As a company, we provide web hosting for a variety of customers. This includes websites as well as interactive services such as Discourse forums and Mastodon federated social media instances.

Aragon Ventures sets only its own privacy practices, not the practices of our customers or others who utilize our web hosting services for themselves or for others. You should ask all those involved with the administration or operation of websites hosted with us for information about their privacy practices.

How does Aragon Ventures collect data about me?
-----------------------------------------------

Aragon Ventures collects data about you:

* When you browse a website, forum, or other service that Aragon Ventures hosts.
* When you create an account on a website, forum, or other service that Aragon Ventures hosts.
* When you post, send private messages, or otherwise participate on a website, forum, or other service that Aragon Ventures hosts.

Aragon Ventures will collect this data regardless of browser, device, or app used to access our services.

Aragon Ventures does not buy or otherwise receive data about you from data brokers.

What data does Aragon Ventures collect about me, and why?
---------------------------------------------------------

### Aragon Ventures collects data about visits to website, forums, or other services.

When you visit a website that Aragon Ventures hosts, regardless of whether you have an account or not, the website may use cookies, server logs, and other methods to collect data about what pages you visit, when, and how.

Aragon Ventures uses this data to:

* Optimize websites and services, so that they are quick and easy to use.
* Diagnose and debug technical errors.
* Defend websites and services from abuse and technical attacks.
* Compile statistics on the popularity of a website, page, post, topic, etc.
* Compile statistics on the kinds of software and computers visitors use.

In the event Aragon Ventures stores this data in an identifiable form, this data is usually only retained for a few weeks. In special circumstances—such as extended investigations regarding a technical attack—Aragon Ventures may preserve logged data for longer periods for analysis. Aragon Ventures stores aggregate statistics about use of the websites and services we host indefinitely, but those statistics do not include data identifiable to you personally.

### Aragon Ventures collects account data.

On some websites and services Aragon Ventures hosts, many features may require an account. For example, on forums we operate an account is required to post and reply to topics.

To sign up for most accounts, Aragon Ventures will collect a name, username, email, and password. In the event a website requires more information than just that data, that will be clearly marked and noted in a separate privacy statement, per-site.

Aragon Ventures uses your account data to identify you on the website, and to create pages specific to you, such as your profile page. If the website is public, Aragon Ventures publishes your account data. If the website is access-restricted, Aragon Ventures makes your account data available to everyone who can access the website, including the website administrator’s configuration.

Aragon Ventures uses your email to:

* Notify you about posts and other activity on the websites or services.
* Reset your password and help keep your account secure.
* Contact you in special circumstances related to your account.
* Contact you about legal requests, such as DMCA takedown requests.

On some websites and services you may provide additional information for your account, such as a short biography, avatar, your location, or your birthday. Aragon Ventures makes that information available to everyone who can access the website or service in question. This information is not required to use any of our services, and can be erased at any time.

Aragon Ventures stores your account data as long as your account remains open. After closing an account, Aragon Ventures may retain some or all of your account data in the form of backups or service archives for up to 90 days.

How can I make choices about data collection?
---------------------------------------------

You can make choices about how your data is used and published on the settings page of your account. When a forum or other service uses restrictions that vary by category or post, you can choose who can see your content by choosing the appropriate category or access setting.

Where does Aragon Ventures store data about me?
-----------------------------------------------

Most websites and services hosted by Aragon Ventures reside in OVH’s datacenter in France. Some websites, services, or backups may reside in datacenters in multiple jurisdictions, including the United States and the European Union.

Does Aragon Ventures comply with the EU General Data Protection Regulation?
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Aragon Ventures respects privacy rights under [Regulation (EU) 2016/679](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=uriserv:OJ.L_.2016.119.01.0001.01.ENG), the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). Information that GDPR requires Aragon Ventures to give can be found throughout this document. So can information about specific rights, like [access](#where-can-i-access-data-about-me), [rectification](#how-can-i-change-or-erase-data-about-me), [erasure](#how-can-i-change-or-erase-data-about-me), [data portability](#where-can-i-access-data-about-me), and [objection to automated decision-making](#does-aragon-ventures-make-automated-decisions-about-me).

What are my data protection rights?
-----------------------------------

Aragon Ventures would like to make sure you are fully aware of all of your data protection rights. Every user is entitled to the following:

* **The right to access** – You have the right to request access to your personal data, or copies of your personal data from Aragon Ventures. We may charge you a small fee for providing a copy of your data. In many cases you can view this information yourself, as detailed in our [data access](#where-can-i-access-data-about-me) section.
* **The right to rectification** – You have the right to request that Aragon Enterprises correct any information you believe is inaccurate or incomplete. In many cases you can make changes to your account information yourself, as detailed in our [data change](#how-can-i-change-or-erase-data-about-me) section below.
* **The right to erasure** – You have the right to request that Aragon Ventures erase your personal data, under certain conditions. Please see our section on [data erasure](#how-can-i-change-or-erase-data-about-me) for details.
* **The right to restrict processing** – You have the right to request that Aragon Ventures restrict the processing of your personal data, under certain conditions.
* **The right to object to processing** – You have the right to object to Aragon Ventures’s processing of your personal data, under certain conditions. More details on this processing can be found in our [automated decisions](#does-aragon-ventures-make-automated-decisions-about-me) section below.
* **The right to data portability** – You have the right to request that Aragon Ventures transfer the data that we have collected to another organization, or directly to you, under certain conditions.

Where can I access data about me?
---------------------------------

On most websites and services you can see your account information at any time by visiting your account page. This page will typically also list your activity on the website.

Your account page or website preferences page will provide a link to download all of your activity in a standard format.

On certain services, such as Matrix (Synapse/Riot), your account information will not be available for download directly. In these cases you can request a copy of your data by emailing the service administrator.

How can I change or erase data about me?
----------------------------------------

You can change your account settings at any time by visiting your account’s profile settings page. The settings for some services may also allow you to close your account. Closing your account begins a process of anonymizing or erasing Aragon Ventures’s records of data you provided for your account. Service administrators can also erase and anonymize your account.

Depending on the settings for your particular service, you may also be able to edit, anonymize, or erase your posts. When you edit posts, Aragon Ventures will keep all versions of your post. Service administrators will be able to view previous versions of your post, and optionally make them visible to other visitors.

Does Aragon Ventures make automated decisions about me?
-------------------------------------------------------

### Aragon Ventures classifies posts as spam automatically.

Aragon Ventures uses data about your post and other activity on different services to make automated decisions about whether your posts to the services we host are spam.

If you believe a post has been wrongfully blocked or removed for this reason, contact the administrator of the service. Service administrators will be able to manually override this decision.

### Aragon Ventures uses data about posts and activity to set trust levels automatically.

On Discourse forums hosted by Aragon Ventures, depending on how administrators of your forum configure the forum, the forum may use data about your posts and activity to award you badges and calculate a trust level for your account. Your trust level may affect how you can participate in the forum, such as whether you can upload images, as well as give you access to moderation and management powers in the forum. Your trust level therefore reflects forum administrators’ confidence in you, and their willingness to delegate community management functions, like moderation.

If you think your trust level has been set incorrectly, contact an administrator of your forum. They can manually adjust the trust level of your account.

Does Aragon Ventures share data about me with others?
-----------------------------------------------------

Aragon Ventures shares account data with others as mentioned in the section about account data.

Aragon Ventures shares data about your posts and other activities with others as mentioned in the section about account data.

Apart from making data available to the customer that pays Aragon Ventures to host a website, forum, or other service, Aragon Ventures does not sell or give information about you to other companies or services. However, Aragon Ventures does use services from other companies on some services it hosts. The company behind those services may collect and use your data on their own, for their own purposes. Some of these services may be used to collect information about your online activities from other websites.

| Service | Privacy Notice | Description |
| --- | --- | --- |
| BunnyCDN (SI) | https://bunnycdn.com/privacy | Provides a content delivery network. |
| Cloudflare (US) | https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/ | Provides a content delivery network, DNS services, and visitor analytics. |
| Coinbase (US) | https://www.coinbase.com/legal/privacy | Payment Processing. |
| Hetzner (DE) | https://www.hetzner.com/rechtliches/datenschutz/ | Provides servers and services, in service regions around the world, to host and backup some services. |
| Liberapay (FR) | https://liberapay.com/about/legal | Payment and donation collection and organization. |
| Netlify (US) | https://www.netlify.com/privacy/ | Provides automatic website builds and Pull Request previews. |
| OVH Hosting (CA) | https://www.soyoustart.com/us/terms-and-conditions.xml | Provides servers and services, in service regions around the world, to host and backup some services. |
| PayPal (US) | https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full | Payment Processing. |
| Stripe (US) | https://stripe.com/privacy | Payment Processing. |
| VirMach (US) | https://virmach.com/terms-conditions/ | Provides servers and services, in service regions around the world, to host and backup some services. |
| Wasabi (US) | https://wasabi.com/legal/privacy-policy/ | Provides mass storage services to host large media assets and backup some services. |

Other individuals and companies may also reuse data about you that Aragon Ventures publishes, such as your posts to public services.

How can I contact Aragon Ventures about privacy?
------------------------------------------------

You can send questions and complaints to:

Aragon Ventures LLC  
privacy@aragon.ventures

You may also write to us at:

Aragon Ventures LLC  
5123 W 98th St #1399 Minneapolis MN 55437 United States

For complaints under GDPR more generally, European Union users may lodge complaints with their local data protection supervisory authorities.

How can I find out about changes?
---------------------------------

This version of Aragon Ventures’s privacy questions and answers took effect May 29th, 2023.

Aragon Ventures will post the next version at [https://aragon.ventures/privacy](https://aragon.ventures/privacy). Aragon Ventures may change how it announces changes in future versions of this document.

In the meantime, Aragon Ventures may update its contact information at any time without announcing a change. Please refer to [https://aragon.ventures/privacy](https://aragon.ventures/privacy) for the latest contact information at any time.

© 2020 - 2023 Aragon Ventures LLC
